MOHAMMED KHALED

Web and SharePoint Developer

PERSONAL DETAILS

Email mohammed.khaled.mahmoud1996@gmail.com

Tel +201141226652

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohamed-khaled-abed/

Website https://mohammedkhaled.com

Nationality Egyptian

WORK OBJECTIVES

Online SharePoint and Office365 applications as Power automate, Power BI, Cloud applications and rest of office365 applications with +4 years and Web developer with HTML, CSS, JavaScript and WordPress.

I can develop online SharePoint by using JavaScript, using workflows among office365 applications to automate systems and analyze data entry by Power BI.

I can develop websites or applications by using JavaScript, PHP and I have good knowledge in python to build disktop applications.

I have strong knowledge in WordPress, writing and localizing technical content and using search engine optimization [SEO].

WORK EXPERIENCE

SharePoint developer [7/2019 – present] *Egyptian Red Crescent, Cairo, Egypt*

Information Technology developer [9/2020 – present] Egyptian Red Crescent, Cairo, Egypt

Projects:

- -ISR [IT Standard Requests] (SharePoint, Power automate, Outlook, Forms)
- ⇒ Create users request automatically.
- ⇒ Decreased time and save effort 60%.
- ⇒ SharePoint pushed users data to approvals to approve or reject request and save users data automatically in database.

Automation specialist [9/2019 - 1/2020]

Egyptian Red Crescent [ERC], Cairo, Egypt

Projects:

- -SharePoint projects (SharePoint, Power automate, Power bi)
 - Create data entry and indicate power automate and power Bi
 - Analyses data on power Bi to get accurate statistics
 - ⇒ Export data offline on excel
 - ⇒ save great amount of data in secured database
 - ⇒ create +10 systems using SharePoint with different types of forms as medical, contact, calendar, etc

SharePoint developer [10/2019 - present]

Egyptian Red Crescent [ERC], Cairo, Egypt Services and Helps

Projects:

-Profile(Personal Website (https://mohammedkhaled.com/profile)) (HTML, CSS, JS)

Web developer [12/2020 – present]

My portfolio helps you to find me and look forward to my projects **Projects:**

- Touch typing game (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript)

Web Developer [10/2021]

This game helps you to measure touch typing skill and count your errors and estimated time for typing

Projects:

-Note taker (online web application) (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery)

Web Developer [7/2022]

This application helps to save your notes on your browser by using local storage and you can export your notes to Excel or PDF and This application considers visualization for SharePoint application

EDUCATION QUALIFICATIONS

Bachelor of art (Spanish is major) (English is minor) [9/2015 – 6/ 2019] Faculty of Al-Alsun

Ain Shams University (http://www.shams.edu.eg) - Good Cairo, Egypt

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Core Skills

Back-end ison **Project** Python HTML Management: CSS3/BEM PHP **SharePoint skills** ES6

JS Azure Online SharePoint **Typescript Automate** MYSQL Concepts

JavaScript/JS BI OOP API **VSC**

API

JavaScript Material **ECMAScript** Native JavaScript

Bonus Skills

WordPress - Bootstrap - search engine optimization [SEO] - CMD - batch file - GitHub

NTP+

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Arabic: Native Spanish: basic **English:** *fluent*

CERTIFICATES

ICDL[International Computing Drive License] (6/2016) Computer Qualified Center, Cairo, Egypt

Online courses in Web and SharePoint development on different platforms